First thing we do is we work closely with our marketing partners.
首先我们与营销合作伙伴紧密合作
They are interested in a number of different things that might be tested.
他们对多个可能会测试的指标感兴趣
There's always new ideas,
始终都会出现新的想法
and there are a couple different categories of those new ideas too,
这些新想法可以归属到几个不同的类别
or the major requests so a new feature in the app or
例如重大请求 新的应用功能
a substantial change to the loyalty program would
或者大幅更改积分计划
mean quite a bit of work not just on the data science side,
这些不仅给数据科学家带来大量工作
not just on the modeling side,
不仅会影响到建模人员
but also everyone around the building would be impacted,
而且会影响到企业内的所有人员
and more importantly, customers and the partners and
更重要的是 消费者、合作伙伴和咖啡店
our stores would be impacted by it too.
也会受到影响
So, first question is the customer going to get it, right?
首要问题是客户会受影响吗？
Pretty much any customer facing change that we produce is
几乎所有面向客户的更改
going to end up being a question that goes to a barista somewhere.
最终都会变成影响到咖啡师的问题
So, is this experiment going to
我们还需要考虑
impact the operations in the stores is another thing that we have to be considering.
这项实验会影响到咖啡店里的运营情况吗？
So, we do have a lot of data.
我们有很多数据
We have data coming in from different sources,
这些数据来自不同的来源
we have data coming in from the stores themselves,
有些数据来自店面
there's inventory data, there's data from the registers,
有些数据来自注册人员
there's data comes in from the app.
有些数据来自应用 还包括库存数据
It comes in from many places.
这些数据来自很多渠道
We do take a look at this and try and decide is there some sort of historical precedent?
我们会研究这些数据 并判断有没有什么历史先例
Is there some reason for hope this idea is going to work out?
有什么理由可以证明这个想法可行吗？
Next question, can we measure the result?
下个问题 我们能衡量结果吗？
Any great idea, we can put it out there,
任何出色的想法都可以实施下去
but are we going to be able to tell if it worked or not?
但是我们能够判断想法是否可行吗？
So, another operational constraint there.
这是需要考虑的另一个运营约束条件
I would hope that most of the time,
我认为大部分情况下
most experiments would fail.
大多数实验都会失败
It's pretty normal.
这很正常
If we had an idea that we were so certain would work,
如果有一个想法我们很确定能够成功
and if we had 10 such ideas like that and nine of them worked,
如果有十个此类想法 九个都能成功
why weren't we already doing them?
那为何不早就采用这些想法呢？
Those are the obvious things.
这些是很明显的事实
Data science is here to uncover the less obvious.
我们需要数据科学来挖掘不明显的事实
So, yes.
所以
We run experiments all the time.
我们一直都在开展实验
Now, they don't typically fail in grand fashion.
它们并没有失败的很惨
It's not usually a disaster,
通常并不是糟糕的结果
but very often, the result is little to minimal change.
但是结果带来的变化很小
Even if you get a somewhat positive result,
即使得到某种正面结果
is it worth the effort to take that experiment and lift it into the production setting?
有必要将这种实验推广到生产环境吗？
Demographic feature is a broadly term.
人口学特征是一个很宽泛的词
So, how long has someone been a member of the program, for example.
例如 某人成为计划会员有多长时间了
Then, treatment history.
然后看看处理历史记录
What have we tried showing you before?
之前尝试展示了什么样的数据？
So, somebody, maybe not specifically which exact to offer have we shown you before,
之前收到优惠的人 可能没有具体确定是哪个优惠
but somebody who is in a group that is used to receiving offers
组内之前收到优惠的人
behaves differently than somebody in a group who's not used to receiving offers.
与组内之前没有收到优惠的人行为不一样
Time is a variable that matters an awful lot to us.
时间是一个非常重要的变量
In fact, we're about to enter your holiday period.
实际上 马上要到节日了
People behave very differently at Starbucks between Thanksgiving and
在美国的感恩节（11月）和圣诞节（12月）期间
Christmas in the US than they do during the rest of the year.
人们在星巴克的消费行为与一年中的其他时间差别很大
So, a control that is somebody might make a good control in October,
所以 十月份的消费者可以作为很好的对照组
but a poor control in November for those sorts of reasons.
而十一月份的消费者则不行